Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm Microfilm Investigations, 1913-1950 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- 16mm Investigations, 1913-1950 and undated
  - General Cigar Company
    - General Cigar Bk. 4
      - Analysis of questionnaires returned by smokers of White Owl, 1937 July
      - Dealer and consumer survey in Cleveland, Philadelphia and St. Louis; memos, 1938 Feb.
    - General Cigar Bk. 5
      - White Owl consumer and dealer survey in Washington, D.C. and Pittsburgh; also plan of survey in 5 cities (Philadelphia, Cleveland, St. Louis, Washington, Pittsburgh), 1938 June
      - U.S. revenue figures on cigars and cigarettes since 1910, 1938 Sept.
      - White Owl dealer survey in N.Y. and vicinity, 1938 Nov.
      - Consumer survey on cigar advertising, 1938 Nov.
      - Additional information on White Owl consumer and dealer survey, 1938 Nov.
      - White Owl dealer survey in 5 cities, 1939 Aug.
    - General Cigar Bk. 6
      - Survey of cigar smokers in New York, 1939 Oct.
      - Comparison of consumer purchase survey with JWT cigar survey in the N.Y. market, 1939 Nov.
      - General Cigar consumer sampling plan, 1940 Jan.
      - Dealer and consumer survey in Dallas, Tex., 1940 Apr.
      - White Owl shipments in thousands, 1940 Feb.
      - White Owl check-back on sampling, 1940 May
  - Lever Brothers
    - Lux Flakes Bk. 10
      - Lux Flakes bath test and re-checks made in Aug., 1937 Sept.
      - Comic strip advertisements, 1937 Oct.
      - Re-check of Lux Flakes for bathtub ring, 1938 Oct.
    - Lux Flakes Bk. 11
      - Premium study, 1937 May
      - Memo on research of jury attitude questionnaire on Lux Radio Theatre, 1937 June
      - Office investigation on hair shampooing, 1937 Sept.
      - Analysis of families by character of population by states, 1937 Dec.
      - Hosiery industry survey, 1938 Jan.
      - Test on Draft and Vel, 1938 Mar.
  - W.F. Young
    - Absorbine Jr. Bk. 2
      - Plan for proposed national consumer survey, 1937 June
      - National consumer survey, 1937 Aug.
      - Analysis of Absorbine and Absorbine Jr. sales by type of market and region, 1937 July
      - Liniment investigation among retail drug outlets in N.Y. City, 1937 Sept.
      - Analysis of market--Absorbine Jr., 1937 Sept.
      - Sales analysis 1935-1936 by type of outlet, 1937 Oct.
      - Tabulation by states of advertised prices of Absorbine Jr., 1937 Oct.
      - Table summarizing miscellaneous data on price maintenance, 1937 Nov.
    - Absorbine Jr. Bk. 3
      - Nationwide dealer survey, 1937 Nov.
      - Trend of drug business, 1937 Dec.
      - Farm horse survey, 1937 Dec.
      - Price check of Absorbine Jr. among independent druggists, 1938 Feb.
      - Sales by type of outlet, 1935-1937, 1938 Mar.
  - Ballantine
    - Ballantine Bk. 2
      - Brown stout test in Hartford and Albany, 1937 Jan.
      - Dealer survey on beer and ale in Newark, 1937 June
      - Market analysis, 1937 Sept.
      - Beer and ale sales and distribution in N.Y.C. (Crossley survey), 1937 Dec.
      - Crossley survey of beer and ale sales and distribution in the Metropolitan area comparing chain outlets with independent grocers and delicatessen stores, 1938 Jan.
      - Ale sales and distribution in the Metropolitan area of N.Y.C.; analysis by economic levels (Crossley survey), 1939 Nov.
      - New York Office survey on beer and ale, 1939 Nov.
      - Ballantine market analysis, 1939 Dec.
      - Beer consumption and advertising costs, 1939 Dec.
      - Proposed plan for Ballantine copy tests, 1939 Dec.
    - Ballantine Bk. 3
      - Memo to Mr. Hine re: retail prices of beer and ale in Grand Rapids, 1940 Feb.
      - Ballantine's sales trends, first 4 months Oct. 1939-Jan. 1940, 1940 Mar.
      - Retail price survey of bottled beer and ale, 1940 Mar.
      - Ballantine's sales trends, first 5 months 1939-1940 and first 6 months 1939-1940, 1940 Apr.
      - Retail price survey of bottled beer and ale, 1940 May
      - Ballantine's sales, Apr. 1940, 1940 June
      - Ballantine's sales, trends by geographic regions, 1940 July
      - Ballantine's sales, June 1940, 1940 July
      - Ballantine's sales, July 1940, 1940 Sept.
      - Ballantine's sales, Aug. 1940, 1940 Oct.
      - Ballantine's sales, Sept. 1940, 1940 Dec.
      - Ballantine's sales, Oct. 1940, 1940 Dec.
      - Retail price survey of bottled beer and ale in groceries and delicatessens, 1941 Jan.
      - Retail price survey of bottled beer and ale in bars and restaurants, 1941 Jan.
      - Ballantine's sales, total, 3 months Oct.-Dec. 1940 compared to Oct.-Dec. 1939, 1941 Feb.
  - Lever Brothers
    - Lever Brothers Bk. 12
      - CBS composite coverage by counties and states in the U.S., 1938 Mar. (Reel 712)
      - Mail survey on influence of Sears Roebuck catalog, 1938 July
    - Lever Brothers Bk. 13
      - Mail (Apr. 1938) and general (Sept. 1937) survey, 1938 Aug.
      - Recognition and location of 74 department stores--New York Office, 1939 Jan.
      - Office surveys on dishwashing habits, lingerie habits and men's opinions on women's stockings, 1939 Jan.
      - Extent to which women knit, crochet and other needlework, 1939 Jan.
      - Name of radio program for Lux soap, 1939 Jan.
      - Recognition and location of 84 department stores--branch offices, 1939 Mar.
      - Screen star poll, 1939 Aug.
      - Test of Lux Active Lather facial, 1939 Aug.
      - Survey on washing habits in N.Y. suburbs, 1939 Aug.
    - Lever Brothers Bk. 14
      - Methods of removing cosmetics--toilet soap, 1939 Sept.
      - Lux toilet soap bath test, 1939 Nov.
      - Consumer test of perfume preference, 1940 Mar.
      - Test of proposed Lux Flakes package, 1940 May
      - CBS study of program audiences and product usage: field word by E. Roper, 1940
      - Memo to Mr. Palmer re: Claim that twice as many women use Lux for silk stockings as use any other flakes, chips or beads, 1940 June
      - Information on soaps recommended for washing nylon hose, 1940 July
      - Office survey on Ivory Flakes and Ivory Snow, 1940 Oct.
      - Nylon wear test, 1940 Dec.
      - Attitude toward nylon hosiery, 1940 Dec.
      - Manufacturers' value in millions of dollars, 1940 Dec.
      - Consumer vote on name for Lux sale tests #1 and #2, 1941 Apr.
      - Plan for nationwide consumer survey of vitamins--New Business, 1941 Apr.
      - Office questionnaire on number of days wear for undergarments, 1941 Apr.
      - Wear test: Ivory Cake vs. Lux Flakes, 1941 Apr.
      - Office questionnaire on use of lanolin in toilet soap, 1941 May
      - Office questionnaire on perfumed toilet soap, 1941 May
      - Lux toilet soap copy test--Whipped cream vs. active lather--Camay and Lux, 1941 May
      - Office survey among women: Lux toilet soap active lather (See Bk. 15 for another report on this test), 1941 May
      - Office survey on washing vs. cleaning of summer dresses, 1941 May
      - Memo to Mr. Palmer re: Further checks on Lux toilet soap, 1941 May
      - 41 names suggested for new headache preparation--New Business, 1941 June
      - Charts and tables on headache remedy market--New Business, 1941 June
      - Drug volume and dealers in test metropolitan markets--New Business, 1941 June
      - Development of a new product headache remedy, 1941 June
      - Office survey among women: Lux toilet soap, 1941 June
      - Rochester drug jobbing area--New Business, 1941 June
  - New Business (Bk. 22)
    - Distribution of Newberry outlets as related to 94 JWT metropolitan markets, 1949 May (?)
    - Electrical appliances survey in Hartford (see also survey below), 1941 May
    - New York Office survey on consumption of orange juice, grapefruit juice and fresh grapefruit, 1941 May
    - Office survey on vitamin content of oranges and grapefruit, 1941 May
    - New York Office survey on automobiles, 1941 May
    - Test in New York and Chicago Offices of JWT on juice content and cost of Florida oranges vs. California oranges, 1941 May
    - Nationwide survey of Regal Shoe Company customers, 1941 Aug.
    - Additional tabulation on General Electric Hartford survey (see also survey above), 1941 Sept.
    - Survey among young men and parents on attitudes towards the Marines, 1941 Sept.
    - Freshmen undersink cabinets, 1941 Oct.
    - Plan for nationwide U.S. Marines Corps survey, 1941 Oct.
  - Owens Illinois Glass Company Bk. 1
    - Dealer survey on War Conservation posters, 1943 Dec.
    - Owens Illinois Glass present consumer advertising budget, 1944 Feb.
    - Summarization of Decoware survey, 1944 Apr.
    - Consumer Panel survey, 1944 May
    - Kitchen Predictions tabulation, 1944 May
    - Bathtub test on coffee containers, 1944 May
    - Coffee container test, 1944 June
  - Penick and Ford (Bk. 3)
    - Br'er Rabbit molasses test among children, 1933 Aug.
    - Memo to Wm. Resor re: Kind of cake women like to eat with ice cream, 1934 Mar.
    - Charts: syrup sales in 180 California stores of a large grocery chain, 1934 Sept.
    - Memo to Wm. Resor re: New Vermont Maid syrup bottle, 1934 Nov.
    - Retail meat prices in New Orleans; Comparison of nutritional values of molasses, pure sugar and various meats on a pound-basis; excerpts from books on the nutrition of molasses, 1935 Feb.
    - Preliminary report on gingerbread flour, 1936 Mar.
    - Final report on gingerbread flour, 1936 Mar.
    - Memo to Wm. Resor re: New Vermont Maid packaging problem, 1936 May
    - Report on consumers who used Br'er Rabbit gingerbread flour in Hartford and Worcester, 1936 May
    - Mail survey among readers of Farm & Ranch, Holland's Magazine, 1936 May
    - Consumer survey on Br'er Rabbit gingerbread flour in Hartford and Albany, 1937 Mar.
    - Br'er Rabbit molasses mail survey in Hartford and Albany, 1937 Mar.
    - Kitchen test on molasses in milk, 1937 Apr.
    - Nationwide consumer survey on syrup, 1937 Apr.
    - Nationwide consumer survey on molasses, 1937 May
    - Office investigation on syrup containers, 1937 May
  - Lamont-Corliss (Pond's)
    - Lamont-Corliss Bk. 11
      - Comparisons of approximate sales of toilet articles, 1938 Feb.
      - Comparison of brands of cold cream used in 1927, 1934, 1936, 1938 Feb.
      - Dealer check on facial cleansing pads, 1938 Feb.
      - Comparison of Clark, Hooper and Starch ratings on two advertisements, 1938 Feb.
      - Survey of dealer reaction to Lady Esther changes in price policy, 1938 Mar.
      - Survey of effect of Serv-a-tissue box on Kleenex sales, 1938 Mar.
      - Test of Pond's Cleansing Pads, formula no. 1003, and test of Coolie Cleansing Pads, 1938 Mar.
      - Memo on Farmer's Wife 1937 survey, 1938 Mar.
      - Analysis of 1937 sales by cities over 25,000 population, 1938 Apr.
      - Miscellaneous information on Lehn & Fink, 1938 Apr.
      - Letter on Pond's Radio Program, 1938 May
      - Kathlyn Mary Quinlan lipstick test, 1938 May
      - Face cream and face powder consumer survey, 1938 June
    - Lamont-Corliss Bk. 12
      - Pond's Cleansing Pads, 1938 June
      - Test of Pond's Cleansing Pads--formula no. 1003 in Miami, 1938 July
      - Test of Pond's Cleansing Pads--formula no. 1007, 1938 Aug.
      - Face cream survey in N.Y. City and suburban Long Island among chain and independent drug stores, 1938 Aug.
      - Pond's Cleansing Pads labeled A and B, 1938 Sept.
      - Analysis of face cream and Pond's sales by markets, 1938 Oct.
      - Pond's new powder shades tests, 1938 Oct.
      - Pond's Cleansing Pad test, 1008 vs. 1009, 1938 Dec.
    - Lamont-Corliss Bk. 13
      - Preliminary resume of Pond's Radio Request Survey (no report), 1939 Jan.
      - Department store and drug store sales, 1939 Jan.
      - Cleansing pad test--1007A vs. 1009A, 1939 Feb.
      - Pond's jobs 1936-1938, 1939 Feb.
      - Weighted index of drug, variety and department store sales in the U.S., 1939 Feb.
      - Test of special tissues, 1939 Mar.
      - Chart on trend of programs: Those We Love in comparison with other leading dramatic shows, 1939 Mar.
      - Trend of Pond's Cream sales by territories grouped according to the share that radio represented of the total budget for 1938, 1939 Mar.
      - Test of Pond's powder sample #434, 1939 Mar.
      - Cleansing pad test--1007A vs. 1007B, 1939 Apr.
      - Comments on the report, Influence of Those We Love on face cream sales, 1939 Mar.
      - Pond's Powder odor test, 1939 May
      - Test of Pond's Face Powder (#434) in Publication Offices, 1939 May
      - Tissue test, 1939 July
      - Lipstick test, 1939 July
      - Powder test #434 modified, 1939 Aug.
      - Pond's mail survey, 1939 Aug.
      - Office test on cologne and toilet water, 1939 Aug.
    - Lamont-Corliss Bk. 14
      - Drug store survey on Pond's Combination (Face Powder and cold cream deal), 1939 Nov.
      - Consumer test of Pond's lipstick (5), 1939 Nov.
      - U.S. Pond's sales, jars vs. tubes, 1940 Jan.
      - Interviews with teachers regarding Home Makers Educational Service, 1940 Jan.
      - Visual test of Pond's Dusk Rose powder, #1 vs. #2, 1940 Jan.
      - Test of Pond's Face Powder--Rose Brunette and Rose Dawn, 1940 Jan.
      - Pond's Face Powder test, #1 vs. #2 Dusk Rose, 1940 Feb.
      - Test of Pond's lipstick, 1940 Mar.
      - Variety store powder displays, 1940 Apr.
      - Mail survey on Pond's kits and booklets made by Home Makers Educational Service and Forecast Magazine, 1940 Apr.
      - Pond's lipstick test in Publication Offices, 1940 Apr.
      - Consumer survey on paper tissues, 1940 Apr.
    - Lamont-Corliss Bk. 15
      - Office survey on foundation cream and finishing cream, 1940 Apr.
      - Test of Quinlan's Hair Rinse, 1940 May
      - Test of Match lipstick, 1940 May
      - Office test on two Pond's powders, 1940 May
      - Test on New Texture Cream (test #1 Apr. 2, test #2 May 13), 1940 May
      - Pond's test of tissue boxes A and B, 1940 June
      - Test of Pond's Texture Cream, Apr. 2, 1940 June
      - Pond's cream sales by territories arranged in order of sales volume in 1939, 1940 June
      - Test of Pond's-manufactured lipstick, 1940 July
      - Plan for proposed telephone survey of Pond's Emollient Cream in Hartford and Atlanta, 1940 Aug.
      - Memo on Pond's Natural Lipstick, 1940 Sept.
      - Directors' Meeting, 1940 Nov.
      - Test of manufactured lipstick, 1940 Dec.
      - Test of Pond's face powders--#850 vs. Regular, 1940 Dec.
      - Test of Pond's Lips--Publications Office, 1940 Dec.
      - Pond's face powders test, A and B, 1941 Jan.
      - Manufacturers' value in millions of dollars on perfumes, cosmetics and other toilet preparations, 1941 Jan.
      - National Resources Committee survey, 1941 Jan.
    - Lamont-Corliss Bk. 16
      - Pond's movie and radio test, checking results, 1941 Jan.
      - Modern magazines survey 1940, 1941 Jan.
      - Memo from Mr. Henderson--Consumer Panel Jan. 8, 1941 Jan.
      - Advertising expenditures, several cosmetics companies, 1941 Jan.
      - Preference for powder boxes test, 1941 Feb.
      - Pond's Skin Freshener, CA-24A vs. CA-24B, 1941 Feb.
      - Office investigation on lipstick and rouge, 1941 Jan.
      - Test of Pond's Emollient Cream, 1941 Feb.
      - Test of Pond's powders, #13 vs. #41, 1941 Mar.
      - Memo from Miss Waldo on Pond's small-sized tissues, 1941 Apr.
      - Pond's test of small-sized tissues, 1941 Apr.
      - Memo on hand lotions and creams--results of survey on another product, 1941 Mar.
      - Information on tinted foundations and creams, 1941 Apr.
      - Use of astringents or skin fresheners, 1941 Apr.
      - Pond's powder test, S-3 vs. K-1, 1941 Apr.
      - Office test on Pond's Skin Freshener, 3 formulas, 1941 Apr.
      - Test of new formulas of Vanishing Cream, B and C, 1941 Apr.
      - Final report on test of Pond's facial tissues, S-23 vs. S-46, 1941 June
      - Test on Pond's Cheeks and Pond's Lips, 1941 July
  - Life Insurance Presidents
    - Survey of public opinion toward life insurance and life insurance companies--Elmo Roper study, 1938 Nov.
    - Public attitude toward big business, 1939 Apr.
    - Survey of public opinion toward life insurance and life insurance companies--Elmo Roper study, 1938 Nov. (Reel 713)
    - Public attitude toward big business, 1939 Apr.
  - Scott Paper Company
    - Scott Bk. 3
      - Distribution check on facial type toilet tissue, 1939 Apr.
      - The market for household waxed paper, 1939 Apr.
      - 1938 Scott sales by divisions, 1939 June
      - Memo to Mrs. Snyder re: Trial of new Scott towels, 1939 Dec.
      - Consumer test among women of JWT on facial type toilet tissue, 1940 Apr.
      - Home test of Soft-Weve facial type toilet tissue, 1941 Feb.
      - Dealer survey on Scott towels and holders, 1941 Apr.
      - Consumer test of Soft-Weve facial type toilet tissue, 1941 Apr.
    - Scott Bk. 4
      - Memo to S. Dean re: Scott Cleansing Tissue brand name--comparison with results of Scott and JWT test, 1941 Dec.
      - Summary of data on market for cleansing tissues, 1941 Dec.
      - Quality test of cleansing tissues: B (Pond's) vs. A (Handies), C (Kleenex) vs. A (Handies), 1941 Dec.
      - Dealer survey on cleansing tissues, toilet tissues and paper towels, 1942 Jan.
      - Consumer Panel survey on cleansing tissues, 1942 Jan.
      - Outline of survey to be conducted among people replying to 50-cent waste basket offer, 1942 Mar.
  - Standard Brands
    - Standard Brands Bk. 19
      - Beech-Nut packing and Procter & Gamble delivery and pricing, 1940 Jan.
      - Salted Nuts--general information, 1940 May
      - Salted Nuts--further information, 1940 May
      - Sales of confectionary in the U.S., 1940 May
      - AMA Seal of Acceptance: Effect of Seal on selection of brand of advertised products, 1940 June
      - Turnover of grocery products, independent retail stores, 1940 June
      - Sales rating vs. index of buying power by Standard Brands foreign division territories, 1940 Aug.
      - Test of two hot chocolates, 1941 Feb.
      - Standard Brands Limited sales charts, 1941 Apr.
      - Food expenditures by family income groups, urban vs. rural, 1941 Apr.
      - Operating income, foreign subsidiaries--charts, 1941 Apr.
      - Surveys on enriched bread, 1941 Oct.
      - Analysis and data for some important ratios of various advertisers (Compton Advertising Company), 1942 May
      - Flour and bread consumption trends (inserted copy, Feb. 28, 1940), 1941 Jan.
      - Fleischmann's yeast for bread--Flour and bread consumption trends, 1940 May
    - Standard Brands Bk. 20
      - Charts--division of Widlar retail and bulk business, 1942 June
      - Consumer sales of gelatins and puddings (Nielsen figures), 1942 Aug.
      - Office survey on beverages, 1942 Sept.
      - Memo to Mr. Young re: Rationing, 1942 Dec.
      - Office test on Golden Rise mix, 1943 Apr.
      - Consumer Panel survey on prepared mixes, May, 1943 June
      - Postwar grocery distribution, 1943 July
      - Leading cereal producers and their advertising expenditures, 1943 Sept.
      - Food business in the U.S., 1945 Mar.
      - Memo to Mr. Baillie re: CAB and Hooper ratings, 1945 Apr.
      - List of continuing newspaper surveys in the grocery field, 1946 Aug.
  - Readership Studies
    - Readership study of the Johns-Manville advertisement and comparable advertisements appearing in the Palladium-Item, 1949 Jan. 27-28
    - Readership study of the Johns-Manville advertisement and comparable advertisements appearing in the Manville Journal, Manville News, Somerset Messenger-Gazette, Bound Brook Chronicle, Raritan Valley News, 1949 Jan. 27-28
    - Readership study of the Johns-Manville advertisement and comparable advertisements appearing in the Manville Journal, Somerset Messenger-Gazette, Bound Brook Chronicle, Raritan Valley News, 1949 Feb. 3-4
    - Readership study of the Johns-Manville advertisement and comparable advertisements appearing in the Palladium-Item, 1949 Feb. 3-4
    - Readership by women of the Mentholatum advertisements and other comparable advertisements appearing in the Palladium-Item, undated
    - Readership by women of the Mentholatum advertisements and other comparable advertisements appearing in Metropolitan Group Comics, undated
    - Readership of advertisements in the Pacific Coast edition of the Metropolitan Group Comics, 1949 Jan. 30
    - Readership of advertisements in the Pacific Coast edition of the Metropolitan Group Comics, 1949 Feb. 27
    - Readership of advertisements in the Pacific Coast edition of the Metropolitan Group Comics, 1949 July 10
    - Readership of advertisements in the Pacific Coast edition of the Metropolitan Group Comics, 1949 July 24
    - Readership of advertisements in the Pacific Coast edition of the Metropolitan Group Comics, 1949 Aug. 7
    - Starch advertisement--reader Buyometer (Reg. U.S. Patent Office)--cigarettes, Saturday Evening Post, undated
    - Sample Starch Buyometer Report, Saturday Evening Post, 1946 Mar. 16
    - Familiarity of readers of Time Magazine with cigarette brands, 1950 Mar. 20
    - Familiarity of readers of Time Magazine with cigarette brands, 1950 Apr. 4
    - Starch Buyometer charts, undated
    - Familiarity of readers of Time Magazine with cigarette brands, 1950 Apr. 17
    - Market for dentifrices--Mexico, 1947 June
    - Market for dentifrices--Mexico, Buenos Aires, Havana, 1947 July
  - Standard Brands
    - Cuban survey, 1945
    - Puerto Rican survey, 1945